Ashley Horton

Email: <u>Ashtomhorton@gmail.com</u>

Website: Ash-Horton.co.uk

Profile

I have recently completed the second year of BSc Physics at the University of Bristol. Since leaving my role as a vehicle mechanic in the Army in 2017, I have worked as an auto fitter at Halfords and as part of the site maintenance team at Gloverspiece Minifarm and school. These roles have given me a well-rounded knowledge base and practical ability of mechanical maintenance and general DIY tasks. I have excellent time keeping skills and will achieve tasks set to a time frame and carry them out to a high standard.

Qualifications

Construction Skills Certification Scheme (CSCS) - Gold skill card

NVQ Level 3 (2012-2017) - Diploma in Equipment Maintenance Engineering

Engineering Technician - Institution of Mechanical Engineers

Education

BSc Physics with Astrophysics, University of Bristol (2018-Present)

Access to Engineering Technology, Bmet College (2017-2018) - Distinction

GCSEs (2010-2012) - GCSEs at grade A*- C including English and Mathematics

Experience

June 2019 - August 2019 Halfords - Auto Fitter

I worked at Halfords as an auto fitter during my summer break from university. My role varied from fitting batteries and bulbs to customers vehicles, to serving customers at the main checkout. My previous experience working with cars as a mechanic allowed me to pick up this role very quickly which resulted in opportunities for quick progression within the company. This job gave me valuable experience in retail and customer service.

October 2017 – June 2018 Gloverspiece Minifarm and School - Site team

While studying at college I worked at a minifarm and school as part of the site team. My role was to complete general maintenance on the site and on the farm's machinery. This would include fixing and putting up fences, repairing and building animal enclosures and servicing the tractors and other machinery as required. These tasks would often be completed on my own with little or no supervision, with the exception of larger tasks which would require me to work with others in a team.

October 2011 – October 2017, continued as Army reservist. Army Vehicle Mechanic

Upon finishing school, I joined the Army and after six months of basic training and one year of trade training, I began working at 7 Transport Regiment as a vehicle mechanic. My main role in the workshop was completing vehicle maintenance and repairs on Land Rovers and MAN trucks. When I started this role, I was working under a more experienced mechanic as an apprentice, but as my knowledge and skills grew, I began to work more independently until eventually taking on apprentices of my own and becoming a mentor to newly qualified mechanics. Since joining the reserves, I have become a class 1 vehicle mechanic and achieved professional recognition as an engineering technician within the Institute of Mechanical Engineers.

Other Skills and Interests

- Driving licence I have a full clean driving licence. I have a full C+E licence, and a category H tracked vehicle licence. I hold a valid certificate of professional competence.
- Escape rooms My partner and myself enjoy attempting escape rooms and together
 have tried to escape from over 50 different rooms, including two in Greece and one in
 Spain. There are very few rooms we have failed to escape from and I embrace any
 opportunity to test my knowledge and problem-solving ability.
- Skydiving While in the Army, I completed over 900 skydives including over 30 parachute displays, mostly into large high profile events such as the Bournemouth air festival, Torbay air show and into Canterbury cricket ground. I am now a qualified tandem skydiving instructor making me responsible for a group of students before their jump and the safety of the student that I complete the skydive with.